College English Test, Band 6, Part 2, Listening Comprehension.
Section A, Directions.
In this section, you will hear two long conversations.
At the end of each conversation, you will hear four questions.
Both the conversation and the questions will be spoken only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices
marked A, B, C, and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1 with a single line through the
center. Conversation 1.
Now, could you tell me where the idea for the business first came from?
Well, the original shop was opened by a retired printer by name of Groobie.
Mr. Groobie, being left -handed himself, thought of the idea to try and promote a
few products for left -handers.
And how did he then go about actually setting up the business?
Well, he looked for any left -handed products that might already be on the market,
which were very few, and then contacted manufacturers with the idea of having
products produced for him, mainly in the scissor range to start with.
Right. So you do commission some part of your stock.
Yes, very much so.
About 75 of our stock is specially made for us.
And the rest of the rest of it now, some 25, 30 years after Mr.
Groobie's initial efforts, there are more left -handed products actually on the
market. Manufacturers are now beginning to see that there is a market for left
-handed products. And what's the range of your stock?
The range consists of a variety of scissors, from children's scissors to scissors
for tailors, hairdressers, etc.
We also have a large range of kitchenware.
What's the competition like?
Do you have quite a lot of competition?
There are other people in the business now as specialists, but only as mail -order
outlets. But we have a here in central London plus a mail -order outlet, and we are,
without any doubt, the largest supplier of left -handed items.
Questions 1 to 4 are based on the conversation you have just heard.
Question 1. What kind of business is the man engaged in?
Question 2. What does the man say about his stock of products?
Question 3. What can we know about the business of left -handed products?
Question 4. man 5.
in? Question 4.
What does the man say about other people in his line of business?
Conversation 2. Can we make you an offer?
We would like to run the campaign for four extra weeks.
Well, we summarize the problem from our point of view?
First of all, the campaign was late.
It missed two important trade fairs.
The ads also did not appear in two key magazines.
As a result, the campaign failed.
Do you accept that summary of what happened?
Well, the delay wasn't entirely our fault.
You did, in fact, make late changes to the specifications of the advertisements.
Hmm. Actually, you were late with the initial proposals, so we had very little time.
And in fact, we only asked for small changes.
Well, whatever. Can we repeat our offer to run the for four extra weeks?
That's not really the point.
The campaign missed two key trade fairs.
Because of this, we're asking you either to repeat the campaign next year for free,
or we only pay 50 of the fee for this year.
Could we suggest a 20 reduction to the fee, together with a four weeks extension to
the campaign? We are not happy.
We lost business.
I think we both made mistakes.
The responsibility is on both sides.
Okay. Let's suggest a new solution.
How about a 40 cut in fee, or a free repeat campaign?
Well, let's take a break.
We're not getting very far.
Perhaps we should think about this.
Questions 5 to 8 are based on the conversation you have just heard.
Question 5. What do we learn about the man's company?
Question 6. Why was the campaign delayed according to the man?
Question 7. What does the woman propose as a solution to the problem?
Question 8. What does the man suggest they do at the end of the conversation?
Section B. Directions.
In this section, you will hear two passages.
At the end of each passage, you will hear three or four questions.
Both the passage and the questions will be spoken only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices,
marked A, B, C, and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1, with a single line through the
center. Passage 1.
The University of Tennessee's Walters Life Sciences Building is a model animal
facility, spotlessly clean, careful in obtaining prior approval for experiments from
an animal care committee.
Of the 15,000 mice housed there in a typical year, most give their lives for
humanity. These are good mice and as such warrant the protection of the animal care
committee. At any given time, however, some mice escape and run free.
These mice are pests.
They can disrupt experiments with the bacterial organisms they carry.
They are bad mice and must be captured and destroyed.
Usually, this is accomplished by means of sticky traps, a kind of fly paper on which
they become increasingly stuck.
But the real point of this cautionary tale, says animal behaviorist Herzog, is that
the labels we put on things can affect our moral responses to them.
Using stick traps, or the more deadly snap traps, would be deemed unacceptable for
good mice. Yet the killing of bad mice requires no prior approval.
Once a research animal hits the floor and becomes an escapee, says Herzog, its moral
standing is instantly diminished.
In Herzog's own home, there was a more ironic example.
When his young son's pet mouse, Willie, died recently, it was accorded a tearful
ceremonial burial in the garden.
Yet even as they mourned Willie, says Herzog, he and his wife were setting snap
traps to kill the pest mice in their kitchen.
With the bare change in labels from pet to pest, the kitchen mice attained a totally
different moral status.
Questions 9 to 12 are based on the passage you have just heard.
Question 9. What does the passage say about most of the mice used for experiments?
Question 10. Why do the so -called bad mice have to be captured and
Question 11. When are mice killed without prior approval?
Question 12. Why does the speaker say what the Herzogs did at home is ironical?
Question 13. Passage 2.
There are roughly three New Yorks.
There is first the New York of the man or woman who was born here, who takes the
city for granted and accepts its size and its turbulence as natural and inevitable.
Second, there is the New York of the commuter, the city that is swallowed up by
locusts each day and spat out each night.
Third, there is the New York of the person who was born somewhere else and came to
New York in quest of something.
Of these three trembling cities, the greatest is the last, the city of final
destination, the city that is a goal.
It is this third city that accounts for New York's high strong disposition, its
dedication to the arts, and its incomparable achievements.
Commuters give the city its tidal restlessness, natives give it solidity and
continuity, the settlers give it passion.
And whether it is a farmer arriving from Italy to set up a small grocery store in a
slum, or young girl arriving from a small town in Mississippi to escape the
indignity of being observed by her neighbors, or a boy arriving from the Corn Belt
with a manuscript in his suitcase and a pain in his heart, it makes no difference.
Each embraces New York with the intense excitement of first love, each absorbs New
with the fresh eyes of an adventurer, each generates heat and light to dwarf the
consolidated Edison Company.
Questions 13 to 15 are based on the passage you have just heard.
Question 13. What does the speaker say about the natives of New York?
Question 14. What does the speaker say commuters give to New York?
Question 15. What do we learn about the settlers of New York?
Section C Directions
In this section you will hear three recordings of lectures or talks, followed by
three or four questions.
The recordings will be played only once.
After you hear a question you must choose the best answer from the four choices
marked A, B, C, and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1, with a single line through the
center. Recording 1.
Good evening ladies and gentlemen.
Today we are honored to have Professor Dreiser from the Johns Hopkins University.
He will introduce to us the study of the relationship between health and nutrition
utilization. Professor Dreiser, please.
Thank you for your introduction, Kara.
Well, the study of the relationship between health and how the body takes in and
utilizes food substances can be divided into four distinct eras.
The first era began in the 19th century and extended into the early 20th century,
when it was recognized for the first time that food contained components that were
essential for human function, and that different foods provided different amounts of
these essential agents.
Near the end of this era, research studies demonstrated that rapid weight loss was
associated with nutrition imbalance, and could only be rectified by providing
adequate dietary protein associated with certain foods.
The second era was initiated in the early decades of the 20th century, and might be
called the vitamin period.
Vitamins came to be recognized in foods, and deficiency syndromes were described.
As vitamins became recognized as essential food constituents necessary for health,
it became tempting to suggest that every disease and condition for which there had
been no previous effective treatment might be responsive to vitamin therapy.
At that point in time, medical schools started to become more interested in having
their curricula integrate nutritional concepts into the basic sciences.
Much of focus of this education was on the recognition of vitamin deficiency
symptoms. Herein lay the beginning of what ultimately turned from ignorance to
denial of the value of nutritional therapies in medicine.
Reckless claims were made for effects of vitamins that went far beyond what could
actually be achieved from the use of them.
In the third era of nutritional history in the early 1950s to mid 1960s, vitamin
therapy began to fall into disrepute.
Together with this, nutrition education in medical schools also became less popular.
It was just a decade before this that many drug companies had found their vitamin
sales skyrocketing, and were quick to supply practicing physicians with generous
samples of vitamins.
Expectations as to the success of vitamins in disease control were exaggerated.
As is known in retrospect, vitamin and mineral therapies are much less effective
when applied to health crisis conditions than when applied to long -term problems of
undernutrition that lead to chronic health problems.
And the fourth era.
16 to 18 are based on the recording you have just heard.
Question 16. According to Professor Dreiser, which of the following discoveries was
made during the first era in the history of nutrition?
Question 17. What is the purpose of teaching concepts of nutrition in medical
schools? Question 18.
Why did vitamin therapy become less popular in the 1950s?
Question Recording 2.
Long before they can actually speak, babies pay special attention to the speech they
hear around them.
Within the first month of their lives, babies' responses to the sound of the human
voice will be different from their responses to other sorts of sounds.
They will stop crying when they hear a person talking, but not if they hear a bell
ring. At first, the sounds that an infant notices might be only those words that
receive the heaviest emphasis and that often occur at the end of sentences.
By the time they are six or seven weeks old, babies can detect the difference
between the rising and falling of tones.
Very soon, these differences in adults' stress and tones can influence babies'
emotional states and behavior.
Long before they develop actual language comprehension, babies can sense when an
adult is cheerful or angry, attempting to do or stop doing something, and so on,
merely based on the rate, volume, and melody of adult speech.
Adults make it as easy as they can for babies to pick up a language by exaggerating
such characteristics.
One researcher observed babies and their mothers in six diverse cultures, and found
that in all six languages, the mothers used simplified grammar, short sentences, and
transformed certain sounds into baby talk.
Other investigators have found that when mothers talk to babies who are only a few
months old, they often raise their volume and speak slowly.
They also exaggerate their facial expressions and emphasize certain words.
significant for language development than their response to general intonation is
observation that tiny babies can make relatively fine distinctions between speech
sounds. In other words, babies enter the world with the ability to make precisely
those perceptual discriminations that are necessary if they are to acquire oral
language. Babies obviously derive pleasure from sound input, too.
At even as young as nine months, they will listen to songs or stories, although the
words themselves are beyond their understanding.
For babies, language is a sensory motor delight, rather than the root to dull
meaning that it often is for adults.
Questions 19 to 22 are based on the recording you have just heard.
Question 19. What does the talk mainly discuss?
Question 20. Why does the speaker mention the ringing of a bell?
Question 21. What can we learn from the findings of babies and their mothers in six
diverse cultures? Question 22.
to the talk, why do babies listen to songs and stories, even though they cannot
understand them? Question
The history of the cinema in its first 30 years is one of major and to this day
unparalleled expansion and growth.
Beginning as something unusual in a handful of big cities New York,
Paris, and Berlin, the new medium quickly found its way across the world, attracting
larger and larger audiences wherever it was shown and replacing other forms of
entertainment as it did so.
Meanwhile, films themselves developed from being short attractions only a couple of
minutes long to the full -length feature that has dominated the world's screens up
to the present day.
Although French, German, American, and British pioneers have all been credited with
the invention of the British and the Germans played a relatively small role in its
worldwide exploitation. It was above all the French followed closely by the
Americans who were the most passionate exporters of the new invention, helping to
start cinema in China, Japan, America, and Russia.
In terms of artistic development, it was again the French and the Americans who took
the lead, though in the years before the First World War, Italy, Denmark, and Russia
also played a part.
In the end, it was the United States that was to become and remain the largest
single market for films.
By protecting their own market and pursuing a vigorous export policy, the Americans
achieved a dominant position on the world market by the start of the First World
War. The center of filmmaking had moved westwards to Hollywood, and it was films
from these new Hollywood studios that flooded onto the world's film markets in the
years after the First World War and have done so ever since.
Faced with total Hollywood domination, few film industries proved competitive.
The Italian industry almost collapsed.
In Scandinavia, the Swedish cinema had a brief period of glory, notably with
powerful epic films and comedies.
Even the French cinema found itself in a difficult position.
In Europe, only Germany proved industrially capable, while in Russia and in Japan,
the development of the cinema took place in conditions of commercial isolation.
Question 24. to the talk, what can we learn about the film market back then?
Question 25. What is the speaker's attitude towards the film industry?
Question 26. This is the end of listening comprehension.